Hasan Ahmed

Boulevard 1945 4, Enschede, 7511AE, The Netherlands

Mobile: +31633426216

Email: hasan.sylh3t@gmail.com Website: https://ahmedhasan.info

LinkedIn: iamhasanahmed

Skill

Research experience on Geographic Information Science (GIS) and Remote Sensing (RS) for Natural Resources, Land Cover, and Change Detection.

Relevant Remote Sensing Skills:

- Satellite Image Analysis
- Synthetic Aperture RADAR (SAR)
- UAV Remote Sensing
- LiDAR Remote Sensing

Relevant Software Skills:

- ArcGIS (Desktop, Pro, Online)
- ERDAS IMAGINE
- QGIS
- ENVI
- ILWIS
- eCognition
- Pix4D
- Agisoft Metashape

Programming languages:

- Python
- R
- Visual Basic

Other Skills:

- Geodatabase Management
- Geoportal Management
- Web Development
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Microsoft Office

Award/Honor

Awarded for current MSc in Groinformation Sciecne and Earth Observation Program:

- ITC Excellence Scholarship
- The Holland Scholarship

Career Objective

Proactive Geo-information Science and Earth Observation major (8.36 CGPA) with specialization on Natural Resources currently attending the University of Twente, with 1.5+ years of work experience. Aiming to leverage a proven knowledge of remote sensing, geoinformation science, and natural resources to successfully build and grow a professional career in a relevant company.

Experience

Research Assistant (Remote)

Centre for Ecology, Environment, and Evolution, University of Lisbon, Portugal January 2018 – December 2018

Worked on analyzing Landsat satellite images for land-cover change detection, conduct fieldwork, draft and submit reports of works to the relevant researcher of the doctoral program of Climate Change and Sustainable Development Policies.

Course Instructor

Forestry Science and Technology Institute, Sylhet

July 2017 – January 2018

Professional diploma course of Bangladesh Forest Department, Ministry of Environment, Forest and Climate Change, only for forest bit officers or ranger. Taught Forest Silviculture, GIS for Forestry, and Forest Inventory courses.

Education

MSc candidate Geo-information Science and Earth Observation

University of Twente, Enschede, The Netherlands

September 2019 – July 2021

CGPA 8.36 out of 10 (US Equivalent: 4.0 out of 4.0)

Specialization on Natural Resources Management

Scholarships: ITC Excellence Scholarship, The Holland Scholarship

MSc in Forestry

Shahjalal University of Science and Technology, Sylhet, Bangladesh

March 2016 – May 2018

CGPA 3.9 out of 4.0

With Distinction

BSc(Honours) in Forestry

Shahjalal University of Science and Technology, Sylhet, Bangladesh

January 2011 - March 2016

CGPA 3.52 out of 4.0

Internship

Intern

Creative Conservation Alliance, Dhaka, Bangladesh

October 2015 – December 2015

Developed maps of python species distribution in Bangladesh using GIS data.

Leadership

Green Explore Society

President (March 2014 - March 2015)

Treasurer (January 2013 – March 2014)

General Member (January 2012 – January 2013)

A student organization concerned for nature conservation and public awareness.

Golap-Bandhan Student Association

Co-founder

University association for the students of a specific community in Sylhet, Bangladesh.